Ringu
Nanako Matsushima
Miki Nakatani
Hiroyuki Sanada
Based on the novel The Ring by Koji Suzuki
Screenplay by Hiroshi Takahashi
Directed by Hideo Nakata
Sunday , September 5
A grade-school boy took a trip to Izu with his family , and they stayed in a cabin .
He wanted to go out and play ...
but there was a TV show he didn 't want to miss .
So he recorded it on the VCR in their room .
But the channels down there are different from Tokyo 's .
No station there uses that channel , so nothing should 've been recorded .
But when he played it back at home , a woman appeared on the screen and said :
" You will die in one week . "
The kid stopped the tape , and then the phone rang .
" You saw it . "
And the kid died a week later !
What 's wrong , Tomoko ?
Who told you that story ?
- Everybody 's talking about it . - Was it Yoko ?
No , not her .
What ?
I saw a weird video the other day .
Where ?
With Yoko and the others .
is it true that you all went on a trip somewhere ?
Nothing happened !
But that night ...
Iwata found this weird video , and we all watched it .
What was it like ?
it 's hard to say .
As soon as it ended , the phone rang .
But nobody was there .
Scary .
Everyone else had heard that story .
Today will be one week .
Come on !
You 're just trying to scare me !
How did you know ?
I can 't believe it !
You 're so easy to fool .
But did you really spend the night there with Iwata ?
- So what happened ? - I 'm not telling !
- Confess ! - it 's a secret .
It was true , wasn 't it ?
Masami !
Hello ?
Hold on a sec .
it 's you , Mom !
A friend came over .
Okay .
Got it .
All right , all right .
Extra innings . They 'll be late .
My parents shouldn 't have scared me like that !
Look who 's talking . I 'm going to tell everyone tomorrow .
I 'm going to the bathroom . Don 't go upstairs without me .
Sure .
On the mound , Takasu , the third player ... .
Everyone 's talking about this deadly video ... .
Yes .
- Have you heard what 's on it ? - Yes .
- Don 't look at the camera . - Sorry .
One more time .
Have you heard what the video is like ?
I heard that suddenly there 's this scary woman ...
who says , " You will die in one week . "
They say she appears when you watch late-night shows on TV .
And then the phone rings .
Late-night shows on TV ? What channel ?
I heard it was on a local channel down in Izu .
- Izu ? - Yeah .
And is there really anyone who died a week later ?
No one that we know .
Well ... .
What ?
A high school student I know told me ...
a girl who watched it died in a car on a date with her boyfriend .
- An accident ? - No . They were found dead in a parked car .
He watched the video , too .
it was in the paper a few days ago .
Do you know which high school she went to ?
No . My friend heard it from a friend of hers .
- Ms . Asakawa . - Yes ?
- Here . - Thanks .
About ten years ago ...
a star killed herself , and people saw her ghost on TV .
Yeah , but this time everyone mentions the Izu Peninsula for some reason .
Well , maybe that 's where this one started .
Where did the story start about the woman with torn lips ?
I think it was Gifu .
There was a big traffic accident there and that 's how it started .
A big accident ?
These stories get started when people die horrible deaths .
- Did something happen in Izu then ? - l don 't know . Well , I have to go .
- Good night . - Good night .
Young Couple Found Dead in Car
A 19-year-old Tokyo boy and a 1 7-year-old Yokohama girl ...
were found dead in a car on the morning of Sept . 6
Take care of it , okay ?
I thought you were leaving early today .
- Okazaki , will you do something for me ? - Sure .
Can you find out which high school she went to ?
No problem .
- Call me when you find it . - Okay .
Yoichi !
Sorry I 'm late . You changed already !
I got your clothes ready , too .
Thanks . We need to hurry .
Did Grandpa call ?
No .
How come Tomoko died ?
Probably some disease .
Zip me up .
Do young people die , too ?
Sometimes they get sick .
But don 't talk about that at Aunt Yoshiki 's , okay ?
it 's too painful for her .
Yeah .
Tomoko used to play with you , didn 't she ?
Dad .
How 's sister ?
She 's lying down . Better leave her alone .
I 'll go help .
Yoichi , you come sit here .
Excuse me .
Reiko .
- Does anyone know how Tomoko died ? - No , I don 't .
But the police did an autopsy !
But there was no evidence of a crime .
People don 't just die like that .
And they never opened the coffin . Isn 't that strange ?
Yoichi .
Don 't play in this room .
- Let 's go downstairs . - Okay .
- Go ahead . - Okay .
Hello ?
It 's Okazaki .
I found the name of the high school .
Seikei Girls ' School in Yokohama .
Thank you .
In Loving Memory - Seikei Girls ' School
Yoko died , too .
Yeah , and Iwata , too ... .
Sorry to interrupt .
Was the girl who died in the car a friend of yours , too ?
If there 's anything you know ... .
All of them died on the same day .
Yoko and Tomoko . And Iwata had a motorcycle accident .
- They saw the video . - The video ?
Yoko told us they 'd all seen this weird video .
When it was over , they got a phone call .
Tomoko saw it , too ? Where ?
They all went and spent the night somewhere .
A girl was with Tomoko when she died .
She went insane and was hospitalized .
She never goes anywhere where there 's a TV .
The girl was Tsuji Yoko , 1 7 , a senior at Seikei Girls ' School .
The boy was Nomi Tadahiko , 19 , a Junior College student .
The car doors were locked .
I 've never seen a corpse look like that .
Cause of death ?
Unknown . Their hearts simply stopped .
Drugs ?
Nothing in the autopsy .
They went up there to make out , then they suddenly died .
it doesn 't make any sense .
I heard that Yoichi came to the funeral .
Yes .
He used to go upstairs and play in Tomoko 's room .
He did .
Photo development receipt
This is where l found Tomoko dead .
Tomoko !
Izu Pacific Land
Izu ... .
l might be late tonight .
Put your supper in the microwave . Okay ?
- Mom ? - Yeah ?
Tomoko watched the cursed video .
Why would you say that ?
Don 't talk about that at school .
I won 't . I 'm going to school now .
Monday , September 13
Izu Parkway
This is crazy !
Izu Pacific Land
... enjoy our hot springs ... .
... the instructor will teach you thoroughly ... .
- Wow , this is roomy ! - Yes , it is .
" My dad 's fat . So is my mom . So I 'm fat , too . "
Are you here alone ?
Yeah , I 'm working .
These four people stayed here on August 29 .
Did you notice anything unusual ?
Just a minute . August 29 ... .
That tape ... .
That one .
What is it ?
This one ?
Someone must have left it .
Eruption
Sada
One week !
Tuesday , September 1 4
is Yoichi in elementary school already ?
First grade .
So how are you , Ryuji ?
The same .
What do you do ?
Teach at a university .
So then there was a phone call ?
Yes .
So this phone will ring after I see it ?
Four people died , all on the same day !
Then get exorcised .
Take my picture .
Face this way .
Hurry up and take it !
it 's over .
No phone call .
Copy this for me . I 'll take a good look at it .
You can 't be sure that you 're going to die .
it 's a video . Someone made it .
I 'll check who stayed there , and if there were any pirate broadcasts .
Wednesday , September 15
From the Izu bureau .
Thanks !
What are you going to do with the cabin registry ?
Sorry , but I just need to check something by myself .
Was it you ?
Did you do this ?
Sorry I 'm late .
What 's wrong ?
Nothing .
So , do you have any new information ?
No one I phoned brought a tape to the cabin .
And they all sounded normal , not like they 'd make a tape like this .
How about pirate stations ?
There 's no record of an illegal broadcast anywhere in Izu .
Here 's the copy .
Asakawa .
Have you ever seen this woman ?
No .
This shot is strange .
From that angle , the cameraman should be in the mirror .
What do you mean ?
I don 't know . You could fix it with special effects , but ... .
" Eruption . "
Which eruption ?
You can 't read it on a regular home TV .
Come in .
This is Takano . One of my students .
Asakawa . My ex-wife .
How do you do ? I 'm Takano .
I 'm Asakawa .
The publisher wants your essay .
Why did they tell you that ?
Because they couldn 't reach you .
Ask for a week extension .
Me ? Ask them yourself !
Okay , okay .
Not clear enough .
" Sada . "
is Yoichi all right alone ?
He 's used to it .
Whoever made this video left a clue subconsciously .
The person wants to be found out .
Wait .
" Frolic in brine , goblins be thine . " it sounded like that .
What does it mean ?
I 'll check tomorrow .
... who says , " You will die in one week . "
They say she appears when you watch late-night shows on TV .
And then the phone rings .
Thursday , September 16
Late-night shows on TV ? What channel ?
I heard it was on a local channel down in Izu .
- Izu ? - Yeah .
Hello ?
I found it . Like I thought , it 's a dialect .
It 's about brine and goblins .
A dialect ? From where ?
Oshima Island , where there 's a volcano , Mt . Miharayama .
Hello , Yoichi ?
I 'll be late tonight .
Yeah .
Are you okay alone ?
I 'm sorry .
This is it , but it happened a long time ago .
Mt . Miharayama Eruption Alert To Local Residents
Did Local Woman Predict Eruption ?
- What is it ? - Does the paper have a bureau in Oshima ?
- l think there 's a correspondent there . - Get me the number . Tonight .
Why ?
You only have four days left .
I 'll handle it with your correspondent .
Please stay with Yoichi .
Grandpa !
Welcome !
Friday , September 1 7
- Yoichi wants to go fishing with you . - Really ?
- C 'mon , let 's go ! - Let 's get ready and go fishing !
Yeah !
Right there .
- Now that way ! - Grandpa ! You 've got one !
We missed it !
You 're not very good at this !
Okay , let 's try it again .
Let 's fish over here this time .
All right .
You 're home .
Hello ?
The correspondent in Oshima did some research for us .
The woman who predicted the eruption is probably the one in the video .
Her name was Yamamura Shizuko .
She threw herself into the volcano 40 years ago .
What do we do now ?
I 'll go down there .
I 'll go to Oshima tomorrow .
Oshima ? But I only have three days left !
I know . And I have four .
I 'll call later .
What 's wrong ?
Nothing . Just doing my work .
Auntie .
Yoichi ?
Yoichi ! Did you bring this ?
How dare you ? Why ?
Tomoko ... .
Tomoko told me to watch it .
I was careless .
I sensed something when I visited your house .
But I thought it was the video .
it was Tomoko .
She 's not Tomoko anymore .
Can Yoichi see her , too ?
it 's all my fault , isn 't it ?
it should have ended with Tomoko and her friends .
I don 't know .
Where did this story come from ?
Nobody starts these kind of stories .
Whatever people feel anxious about becomes rumor and starts to spread .
Anxious ?
Or people start them , hoping things will turn out like this .
Mr. Hayatsu ?
Hello . Sorry you had to come all the way out here .
This way .
Saturday , September 18
The Yamamuras in Sashikiji used to run a big fishery .
But they sold most of their business .
Shizuko 's cousin is still alive .
His son and daughter-in-law run an inn .
I 've booked you there for tonight .
Why did Yamamura Shizuko commit suicide ?
I heard she went insane .
The papers had written awful things about her .
She became famous all over the island after her prediction of the eruption .
She had strange powers all her life .
She was what they call a seer .
After that , a professor showed up . You 've heard of him. lkuma Heihachiro .
Wasn 't he fired ?
He brought Shizuko to Tokyo and experimented on her .
He was trying to prove the existence of ESP .
The papers praised him , then trashed him .
it was 40 years ago , and the media still does the same thing .
I 've heard this story .
If I 'm not mistaken , didn 't someone die in the experiment ?
Dr. lkuma disappeared after his university fired him .
I doubt he 's still alive .
Even if we found him , what could we do ?
They say Shizuko had a daughter .
Hello ?
Hello .
Welcome .
I 'll leave you here .
Please come in .
How many rooms ?
- Two , please . - Yes , sir .
This way , please .
Sir ?
Please .
Wait !
- Please tell me about Shizuko ! - There 's nothing to say .
What about her daughter ?
She didn 't have a daughter .
Not eating ?
No .
When I die , stay with me .
Cut it out .
Please !
Please ? And try to find a way to save Yoichi !
Stop it !
The girl who was with Tomoko lost her mind , huh ?
I don 't know what 'll happen to me .
You 'll be all right !
Because I 'm not normal ?
Maybe all three of us should just die .
Good idea ! We shouldn 't have had a kid in the first place .
Stop it !
We still have two days left .
Excuse me .
Come in .
Did you want to know about Shizuko ?
This is all that 's left .
is this Dr. lkuma ?
Yes. it was before I came here .
Good night .
Thank you .
Frolic in brine ...
goblins be thine .
Sunday , September 19
You 'd better leave this town .
There 's a storm coming tonight .
What was Shizuko like ?
She was a strange one .
She used to sit here all day long .
She 'd just stare at the sea every single day .
All the fishermen hated her .
The sea is ominous for us .
Every year some of us die in the sea .
But she just kept staring at it- -
" Frolic in brine , goblins be thine . "
If you play in the sea , the goblins come to get you .
Shizuko was able to read people 's minds , wasn 't she ?
She must have known about things which people hid deep inside their minds .
That must have been painful .
Go home !
I have similar abilities .
You were the one who spread a rumor about Shizuko 's abilities , weren 't you ?
- You also called Dr. lkuma . - Nonsense !
You thought you could make money off of Shizuko .
You earned money from the newspapers , too .
That 's enough !
Tell me about her daughter ! What happened to her ?
- l don 't know ! - She should have been with Shizuko !
ESP Public Demonstration
You were there ...
when Shizuko gave her demonstration .
Correct .
This is a fraud !
This is just a magic show !
You can 't fool me !
Dr. lkuma , she 's deceiving you , too !
Hey ! What 's wrong ?
He 's dead .
She 's a monster !
Sadako ! Did you do that ?
Sadako ?
Sada
Sadako killed him ?
She could kill someone just by wishing ?
She was a monster !
Sadako !
Hey !
Yes ! After Shizuko killed herself , Dr. lkuma took Sadako with him .
But nobody knows what happened to them since .
Find them !
Dr. lkuma may be dead , but Sadako should be in her 40s .
I 'll explain later . Hurry !
I doubt Sadako is alive , either .
She killed a man just by wishing his death .
Her power was much stronger than her mother 's .
Then that video ... .
it 's not from this world .
it 's Sadako 's wrath .
She 's put a curse on us .
All the ferries have been canceled because the typhoon 's too close .
Try a fishing boat . We 'll pay .
A fishing boat ?
The typhoon might change course . You 'd better wait .
Okay , then I 'll find one !
Mr. Takayama !
Hello ?
Ms. Asakawa ? I 'm sorry , but there 's no trace of either of them .
Thank you .
Yoichi !
Izu !
Ryuji !
Ryuji .
The phone didn 't ring at my house .
The only place it rang was at that cabin !
Dr. lkuma must 've ... .
But we 're stuck here .
You can 't take a boat out on a night like this !
Let me handle this .
Sadako 's calling you , isn 't she ?
Or maybe she 's planning to drag us into the sea .
Take us !
it 's strange , isn 't it ?
I 'm not afraid at all .
Sadako probably died there , before that cabin was built .
Was Sadako Dr. lkuma 's daughter ?
He had a wife and family .
His affair with Shizuko caused a scandal .
That was another reason for his dismissal .
Let 's find Sadako 's corpse .
Will that lift the curse ? Will that save Yoichi ?
There 's nothing else we can do .
I have one day left .
I guess Sadako doesn 't hate you .
Shizuko used to talk to the sea .
She mumbled things to it . She looked like she was having fun .
I hid once and listened .
But it wasn 't a human language .
Monday , September 20
Hello ?
Yoichi ?
it 's Mom . I 'm coming back tomorrow .
I 'm bored here . I want to go back to school !
Don 't say that ! You 'll hurt Grandpa 's feelings !
He 's laughing . Do you want to talk to him ?
That 's okay .
I 'm sorry .
I 'll hurry home .
What 's wrong ?
I still have something to do .
Say hello to Grandpa for me .
What time did you watch the video ?
it was 7 or 8 minutes after 7 : 00 p.m. , but it was before 7 : 10 for sure .
If the story 's true , that will be your deadline .
Here .
- A well , just as I thought ! - A well ?
Her father ?
Dr. lkuma put this lid on . Sadako 's under here .
I 'll go down .
Sadako was still alive !
She tried to climb up .
Lower the buckets !
Pull it up !
it 's 6 : 00 p.m. already !
I know ! Hurry and take it up !
Pull it up !
Asakawa !
Damn it ! Are you trying to kill me ?
Hey !
Asakawa !
Let 's switch .
You can 't lift anymore .
No !
Then who 's going to lift the buckets up ?
We don 't even know if it 'll save us !
Then what about Yoichi ?
You have to pick him up tomorrow !
Don 't look down !
Where are you ?
Come out !
Please ! Where are you ?
it 's you .
Hey ! Asakawa ! it 's past 7 : 10 !
We 're saved !
Why did he kill his own daughter ?
Maybe she wasn 't his daughter .
I wonder if her father was even human .
The marks are gone .
it 's over .
I 'll take you home .
Get some rest . I 've got a deadline for my essay .
Thank you .
Idiot !
Tuesday , September 21
Why ?
Now I got it ! Asakawa !
Are you a resident ?
I 'm Takayama Ryuji 's wife !
The body 's been taken away , ma 'am .
What happened ?
When I got there , he was lying on the floor .
Did he say anything to you ? About a video ?
His face ... .
Why , Ryuji ?
Will Yoichi die , too ?
Didn 't we lift the curse ?
Why was I the only one saved ?
Sadako 's curse was only lifted from me .
Why not you , Ryuji ?
What did I do that you didn 't ?
Ryuji ?
Something I did that you didn 't ...
to lift the curse .
I copied it ...
and showed it to you !
Dad ? Yeah , I 'm on my way .
I have a favor to ask you. it 's for Yoichi .
I heard that there 's a way to lift the curse from the video .
You have to copy it and show it to someone else within a week .
Then what happens to them ?
They have to do the same thing within a week .
Then it never ends ?
That 's right . It goes on forever .
But if you don 't want to die , you 'd do it , wouldn 't you ?
Wednesday , September 22
The RinglThe Spiral Production Group presents in association with Asmik Ace
Entertainment a Omega Project production
( c ) 1998 The RinglThe Spiral Production Group